// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The first european sailor who sighted the island of new guinea?",
    answer: "Jorge de Meneses ",
    options: [
      "Vasco de Gama",
      "Jorge de Meneses ",
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "In what century european sailors discovered the island of new guinea?",
    answer: "16th",
    options: [
      "10th",
      "12th",
      "16th",
      "21st"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Port moresby was named after him?",
    answer: "Captain John Moresby",
    options: [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan",
      "Jorge de Meneses",
      "Captain John Moresby"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In 1884 PNG was split into two, which country colonize the north?",
    answer: "Germany",
    options: [
      "Australia",
      "USA",
      "Great Britain",
      "Germany"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "In 1884 PNG was split into two, which country colonize the south?",
    answer: "Great Britain",
    options: [
      "Australia",
      "USA",
      "Great Britain",
      "Germany"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Who was the first PNG’s Prime Minister?",
    answer: "Michael Thomas Somare",
    options: [
      "Julius Chan",
      "Michael Somare",
      "Michael Thomas Somare",
      "John Guise"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Where is Michael Thomas Somare from?",
    answer: "East Sepik Province",
    options: [
      "Niu Ailan Province",
      "West Sepik Province",
      "East Sepik Province",
      "Morobe Province"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Who was the first PNG’s Governor General?",
    answer: "Sir John Guise",
    options: [
      "Michae Ogio",
      "Sam Basil",
      "Bob Dadae",
      "Sir John Guise"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "When did PNG gain her Self-Government?",
    answer: "1973",
    options: [
      "1975",
      "1970",
      "1973",
      "1972"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "When did PNG gain her independence?",
    answer: "1975",
    options: [
      "1973",
      "1970",
      "1975",
      "1972"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The capital city of PNG?",
    answer: "Port Moresby",
    options: [
      "Hagen",
      "Lae",
      "Port Moresby",
      "NCD"
    ]
  },


  
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The highest peak in PNG?",
    answer: "Mt. Wilhelm",
    options: [
      "Mt. Hagen",
      "Mt. Wilhelm",
      "Mt. Kubar",
      "Star Mountains"
    ]
  },

 
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The longest river in PNG?",
    answer: "Sepik River",
    options: [
      "Waghi River",
      "Markham River",
      "Sepik River",
      "Fly River"
    ]
  },

  

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "The biggest river in PNG?",
    answer: "Fly River",
    options: [
      "Purari River",
      "Ramu River",
      "Sepik River",
      "Fly River"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "The first mission agency to come to PNG?",
    answer: "Catholic",
    options: [
      "Methodist",
      "Catholic",
      "Anglican",
      "Four Square"
    ]
  },

  

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Who designed PNG flag?",
    answer: "Susan Hareho Karike",
    options: [
      "Tei Abel",
      "Paulus Matane",
      "Susan Karike",
      "Susan Hareho Karike"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Where is Susan Hareho Karike from?",
    answer: "Gulf",
    options: [
      "Central",
      "NCD",
      "Gulf",
      "Western"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What do the abbreviation ANGAU stands for?",
    answer: "Australian & New Zealand Administrative Unit",
    options: [
      "Australian New Guinea Administrative Unit",
      "Australian & New Zealand Administrative Unit",
      "Australian New Guinea Admittance Unit",
      "Australian New Guinea Admittable Unit"
    ]
  },


   
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The second largest city in PNG?",
    answer: "Lae",
    options: [
      "Port Moresby",
      "Hagen",
      "Rabaul",
      "Lae"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "The third largest city in PNG?",
    answer: "Hagen",
    options: [
      "Port Moresby",
      "Hagen",
      "Rabaul",
      "Lae"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "When did PNG Unitech established?",
    answer: "1970",
    options: [
      "1975",
      "1970",
      "1960",
      "1965"
    ]
  },
  

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "When did UPNG established?",
    answer: "1965",
    options: [
      "1975",
      "1970",
      "1965",
      "1960"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "The most industrial city in PNG?",
    answer: "Lae",
    options: [
      "Port Moresby",
      "Lae",
      "Hagen",
      "Rabaul"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Who was the first female member of the parliament in PNG?",
    answer: "Dame Josephine Abaijah",
    options: [
      "Lady Carol Kidu",
      "Dame Josephine Abaijah",
      "Hon Kessy Sawang",
      "Rachael Marape"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "The first australian high commissioner to PNG?",
    answer: "Les Johnson",
    options: [
      "Tom Critchley",
      "Les Johnson",
      "Gerry Nutter",
      "John Green"
    ]
  },

  
  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "The second largest island nation in the world?",
    answer: "New Guinea",
    options: [
      "Madagascar",
      "Greenland",
      "New Guinea",
      "Nertherlands"
    ]
  },


  
  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "PNG was the host country that hosts a most significant summit in 2018?",
    answer: "Apec",
    options: [
      "World Health Day",
      "Apec",
      "World Environment Day",
      "Asean Meeting"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "What do the abbreviation APEC stands for?",
    answer: "Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation",
    options: [
      "Asia Pacific Environment Cooperation",
      "Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation",
      "Asia Pacific Ecological Cooperation",
      "Asia Pacific Ecosystem Cooperation"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "The country that gave PNG her independance?",
    answer: "Australia",
    options: [
      "Australia",
      "Great Britain",
      "Germany",
      "Portugal"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "PNG's national bird?",
    answer: "Bird of Paradise",
    options: [
      "Turkey",
      "Cassowary",
      "Bird of Paradise",
      "King fisher"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 31,
    question: "Birdwing butterfly is found in?",
    answer: "Oro",
    options: [
      "Milne Bay",
      "Alotau",
      "Oro",
      "Central"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 32,
    question: "Tapa cloth is found in?",
    answer: "Oro",
    options: [
      "Milne Bay",
      "Oro",
      "Alotau",
      "Central"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 33,
    question: "Hiri trade was practiced in?",
    answer: "Central",
    options: [
      "Hiri",
      "Central",
      "Gulf",
      "Kerema"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 34,
    question: "Kula trade was practiced in?",
    answer: "Milne Bay",
    options: [
      "Hiri",
      "Central",
      "Gulf",
      "Milne Bay"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 35,
    question: "Panguna mine commenced its operation in?",
    answer: "1972",
    options: [
      "1973",
      "1972",
      "1999",
      "1990"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 36,
    question: "Peter O'neill was elected as prime minister in?",
    answer: "2011",
    options: [
      "2009",
      "2010",
      "2011",
      "2012"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 37,
    question: "2020-2021 who was our deputy prime minister?",
    answer: "Sam Basil",
    options: [
      "Belden Namah",
      "Sam Basil",
      "Brian Kramer",
      "John Rosso"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 38,
    question: "Who is our current prime minister?",
    answer: "James Marape",
    options: [
      "Belden Namah",
      "James Marape",
      "Brian Kramer",
      "John Rosso"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 39,
    question: "PNG's development state?",
    answer: "Developing",
    options: [
      "Developed",
      "Improved",
      "Developing",
      "Much More Improved"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 40,
    question: "PNG's current speaker?",
    answer: "Job Pomat",
    options: [
      "Sam Basil Junior",
      "Konny Uguan",
      "Job Pomat",
      "Joseph Lelang"
    ]
  },

  
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];